export default {
  id: 'low_1006_5_1a',
  name: '상용한자(5학년-1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '価', answer: ['값 가', 'あたい', 'か'] },
    { question: '可', answer: ['옳을 가', '옳을', 'か'] },
    { question: '仮', answer: ['거짓 가', 'かり', 'か、[け]'] },
    { question: '刊', answer: ['새길 간', '새길', 'かん'] },
    { question: '幹', answer: ['줄기 간', 'みき', 'かん'] },
    { question: '減', answer: ['덜 감', 'へ(る)、へ(らす)', 'げん'] },
    { question: '講', answer: ['외울 강', '외울', 'こう'] },
    { question: '個', answer: ['낱 개', '낱', 'こ'] },
    { question: '居', answer: ['살 거', 'い(る)', 'きょ'] },
    { question: '件', answer: ['물건 건', '물건', 'けん'] },
    { question: '検', answer: ['검사할 검', '검사할', 'けん'] },
    { question: '格', answer: ['격식 격', '격식', 'かく、[こう]'] },
    { question: '潔', answer: ['깨끗할 결', 'いさぎよ(い)', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '経', answer: ['지날 경', 'へ(る)', 'けい、きょう'] },
    { question: '境', answer: ['지경 경', 'さかい', 'きょう、[けい]'] },
    { question: '耕', answer: ['밭갈 경', 'たがや(す)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '故', answer: ['연고 고', 'ゆえ', 'こ'] },
    { question: '過', answer: ['지날 과', 'す(ぎる)、す(ごす)、あやま(つ)、あやま(ち)', 'か'] },
    { question: '慣', answer: ['익숙할 관', 'な(れる)、な(らす)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '鉱', answer: ['쇳돌 광', '쇳돌', 'こう'] },
    { question: '構', answer: ['얽을 구', 'かま(える)、かま(う)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '句', answer: ['글귀 구', '글귀', 'く'] },
    { question: '久', answer: ['오랠 구', 'ひさ(しい)', 'きゅう、[く]'] },
    { question: '旧', answer: ['옛 구', '옛', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '群', answer: ['무리 군', 'む(れる)、む(れ)、むら', 'ぐん'] },
    { question: '券', answer: ['문서 권', '문서', 'けん'] },
    { question: '規', answer: ['법 규', '법', 'き'] },
    { question: '均', answer: ['고를 균', '고를', 'きん'] },
    { question: '禁', answer: ['금할 금', '금할', 'きん'] },
    { question: '寄', answer: ['부칠 기', 'よ(る)、よ(せる)', 'き'] },
    { question: '基', answer: ['터 기', 'もと、もとい', 'き'] },
    { question: '技', answer: ['재주 기', 'わざ', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '能', answer: ['능할 능', '능할', 'のう'] },
    { question: '団', answer: ['둥글 단', '둥글', 'だん、[とん]'] },
    { question: '断', answer: ['끊을 단', 'た(つ)、ことわ(る)', 'だん'] },
    { question: '貸', answer: ['빌릴 대', 'か(す)', 'たい'] },
    { question: '徳', answer: ['큰 덕', '큰', 'とく'] },
    { question: '導', answer: ['인도할 도', 'みちび(く)', 'どう'] },
    { question: '独', answer: ['홀로 독', 'ひと(り)', 'どく'] },
    { question: '銅', answer: ['구리 동', '구리', 'どう'] },
    { question: '略', answer: ['간략할 략', '간략할', 'りゃく'] },
    { question: '領', answer: ['거느릴 령', '거느릴', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '留', answer: ['머무를 류', 'と(める)、と(まる)', 'りゅう、[る]'] },
    { question: '綿', answer: ['솜 면', 'わた', 'めん'] },
    { question: '夢', answer: ['꿈 몽', 'ゆめ', 'む'] },
    { question: '墓', answer: ['무덤 묘', 'はか', 'ぼ'] },
    { question: '武', answer: ['호반 무', '호반', 'ぶ、む'] },
    { question: '貿', answer: ['무역할 무', '무역할', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '務', answer: ['힘쓸 무', 'つと(める)、つと(まる)', 'む'] },
    { question: '迷', answer: ['미혹할 미', 'まよ(う)', 'めい'] },
    { question: '防', answer: ['막을 방', 'ふせ(ぐ)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '犯', answer: ['범할 범', 'おか(す)', 'はん'] },
    { question: '弁', answer: ['고깔/말씀 변', '고깔/말씀', 'べん'] },
    { question: '保', answer: ['지킬 보', 'たも(つ)', 'ほ'] },
    { question: '報', answer: ['갚을 보', 'むく(いる)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '復', answer: ['회복할 복', '회복할', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '複', answer: ['겹칠 복', '겹칠', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '婦', answer: ['며느리 부', '며느리', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '富', answer: ['부유할 부', 'と(む)、とみ', 'ふ、[ふう]'] },
    { question: '仏', answer: ['부처 불', 'ほとけ', 'ぶつ'] },
    { question: '比', answer: ['견줄 비', 'くら(べる)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '非', answer: ['아닐 비', '아닐', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '備', answer: ['갖출 비', 'そな(える)、そな(わる)', 'び'] },
    { question: '肥', answer: ['살찔 비', 'こ(える)、こえ、こ(やす)、こ(やし)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '貧', answer: ['가난할 빈', 'まず(しい)', 'ひん、びん'] },
    { question: '師', answer: ['스승 사', '스승', 'し'] },
    { question: '査', answer: ['조사할 사', '조사할', 'さ'] },
    { question: '似', answer: ['닮을 사', 'に(る)', 'じ'] },
    { question: '飼', answer: ['기를 사', 'かう', 'し'] },
    { question: '舎', answer: ['집 사', '집', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '謝', answer: ['사례할 사', 'あやま(る)', 'しゃ'] },
    { question: '酸', answer: ['실 산', 'す(い)', 'さん'] },
    { question: '状', answer: ['형상 상', '형상', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '常', answer: ['항상 상', 'つね、とこ', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '像', answer: ['모양 상', '모양', 'ぞう'] },
    { question: '序', answer: ['차례 서', '차례', 'じょ'] },
    { question: '設', answer: ['베풀 설', 'もう(ける)', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '舌', answer: ['혀 설', 'した', 'ぜつ'] },
    { question: '性', answer: ['성품 성', '성품', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '勢', answer: ['형세 세', 'いきお(い)', 'せい'] },
    { question: '税', answer: ['세금 세', '세금', 'ぜい'] },
    { question: '素', answer: ['본디 소', '본디', 'そ、す'] },
    { question: '属', answer: ['무리 속', '무리', 'ぞく'] },
    { question: '損', answer: ['덜 손', 'そこ(なう)、そこ(ねる)', 'そん'] },
    { question: '率', answer: ['거느릴 솔/비율 률', 'ひき(いる)', 'りつ、そつ'] },
    { question: '輸', answer: ['보낼 수', '보낼', 'ゆ'] },
    { question: '授', answer: ['줄 수', 'さず(ける)、さず(かる)', 'じゅ'] },
    { question: '修', answer: ['닦을 수', 'おさ(める)、おさ(まる)', 'しゅう、[しゅ]'] },
    { question: '述', answer: ['펼 술', 'の(べる)', 'じゅつ'] },
    { question: '術', answer: ['재주 술', '재주', 'じゅつ'] }
  ]
}
